livenation.co.uk 2017-09-02

# Live Nation UK

### Privacy Policy 

This Policy explains what personal information [Live Nation and its group](http://www.livenation.co.uk/about) (known in this Policy as “ **we** ” or “ **Live Nation** ”) collect both online (including through apps) and offline and how we use it. Please read it carefully. 

Generally, we collect information about you if you create an account, from your purchase of tickets, when you email or call us, or from box office purchases operated or administered by us, and when you use our websites, apps and social media or any services we may provide during our events such as cashless payment wristband. We use that and other information to provide better services, marketing and support to you and our other customers (including by analysing your information to provide you with a personalised experience). 

When you, for example, create an account, purchase tickets, download one of our apps or contact us on the phone, we may ask your consent to use your information for certain purposes. Your choices about how we use information are described here. 

Live Nation works together with various organisations to bring you the events you love. We call these organisations our Event Partners and these range from, for example, the authorised ticket agents who sell tickets on our behalf, the venues in which our events are held or the artists who we promote. The ticket agents or venues may share your information with us, for the purposes described in this privacy policy. For more detail about how we collect your information click here. For more detail about how we use your information click here. ** __**  

Live Nation is a data controller (i.e. a person responsible for the processing of your personal information) in respect of all of the information which Live Nation collects and receives about you when you use our services.

Live Nation is bound by, and uses your information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

### Cookies Notice 

In common with many online businesses, we use cookies (i.e. small text files that are placed on your computer by our website) and tracking tools. For more information about the cookies on this website and how to disable cookies, please click [here](http://www.livenation.co.uk/cookies). **_ _**

### We collect your information in different ways 

**Directly from you.** For example, if you register for a promotion, create an account, enter a competition or free prize draw, download an app or buy tickets, post a comment on our websites, or get in touch with us in any other way.

**Through your use of our websites and apps.** You may view and use our websites and apps via a computer, phone, tablet or other device. We use tracking tools like browser cookies and web beacons on our websites and apps to collect information about your usage. To learn more, please see our [Cookies Policy](http://www.livenation.co.uk/cookies). 

**Through your use of cashless payment wristbands at our events:** At some of our events you may have to use wristbands equipped with technology to access the event (and areas within the event such as VIP areas) and make cashless payments for things like food and drink by holding the wristband against a reader.  

Through your use of free WIFI at our events: At some of our events, we offer free WIFI for you to keep connected during the events. The use of the service is subject to subscription and to the extent permitted by law, we may use traffic and location data for the purposes set out in this privacy policy. **_ _**

**From our Event Partners.** For example: 

  *  when you buy tickets via our authorised ticket agents, these ticket agents may give us certain information about you.  This includes your name, email and postal address;
  * venues, that host the events you buy tickets for, may give us certain information about you, including your name, email and postal address.  Information about how we use your information is available here. 

**From third parties.** For example: if you choose to use an integrated social media feature on our websites or apps, the third-party social media site will give us certain information about you. This could include your name and email address. Your activities on our sites and apps may be posted to the social media platforms; 

### Information we may hold about you 

We use the following information for the purposes described in this Policy:

**Your contact and account information.** We will hold contact information you provide (e.g. name, address, phone number, email, country of residence, preferred language) when you create an account via our website or via our events branded website, buy a ticket using one of our authorised ticket agents and/or participate in our competitions or promotions. 

**Your payment and billing information.** We will hold payment and billing information you provide to us, e.g. credit card number and post code when you buy a ticket, in connection with the handling of your ticket orders, any merchandise or when you preload or top-up money on your cashless payment wristband. Where necessary, we will hold your bank account details you provide for you to get refund of the outstanding balance on your cashless payment wristband.  If you’ve asked us to, we may also store payment and billing information to make it easier for you to buy tickets in future

**Information you post online.** For example, we hold information you post on our website or on a third-party social media site to which we have access (including reviews you post or surveys you complete). When you post information online, you must not infringe the rights of others (including privacy rights) and you should be aware that others may use, tag and/or re-publish your information in ways that you might not expect (including in ways that are unlawful). You understand that we and others may use and re-publish any data you post online publicly, on our website or when using apps or social media tools. 

**Information on your preferences.** We may collect information about events you like or products you buy or enquire about (e.g. as part of a survey or from your review of an event). We may also hold information on interests and demographic categories inferred from your interactions with us in order to provide you a better service and to provide you with more focused information. For example, if you buy tickets to a certain show and lots of people who went to that show also bought tickets for a different concert, we might send you information about that concert.

**Information from other companies.** We will hold information (e.g. your interests, purchases and household type) provided to us by other companies. We may also add information to your details which we have obtained from other companies or sources. For example, we may cross check the accuracy of the information we hold with other databases, or we may add demographic information. Much of this data is created using publicly available sources such as the edited electoral register or a publically available postal address list, or is derived from market research such as consumer panel surveys.

**Website usage information.** If you use our websites, we may collect information about the browser you're using and your IP address (this is a number that identifies a specific network device on the internet and is required for your device to communicate with websites). We might look at what site you came from, what you did and didn’t use our site for, or what site you visit when you leave us. 

**App(s) usage information.** If you use our app(s), we may collect your GPS location or your device's unique identifier. We might also collect the type of device you are using, or the version of the operating system your computer or device is running. We might look at, for example, how often you use the app and where you downloaded it. Where you allow us to we may also scan your music library when you download our app(s) so that we may send you information about events you may be interested in in your area. Your choices about how we use mobile information are described here. 

**Cashless payment wristband usage information.** If you use a cashless payment wristband during one of our events, we may collect information relating to your use of the wristband such as check-in information and the purchases you make with your cashless payment wristband (i.e. purchase of products and merchandises). 

**Email response information.** In relation to emails we send you, we may collect information on how you respond to such emails, for example, the number of times the email is opened or the links in them are clicked. Please see our [Cookies Policy](http://www.livenation.co.uk/cookies) for more information.

**Other information about your interactions with us.** For example, if you interact with us via a box office, email, telephone or social media (e.g. Facebook). 

### We may use your information in the following ways and for the following purposes 

**To provide you with products, services, account information and support.** For example, we might use your information to confirm your registration for an event. If you give us your friend's information, we will use it to provide services you request from us. Before you give us a friend’s information, please do make sure that you have your friend’s permission to share that information with us.

**To send you communications in connection with your transaction and events you attend.** For example, we might send you emails about your account or a ticket purchase or ask you if you would like to review an event you attended. We might also contact you about this Policy or any of our other policies or terms.

**To identify trends and interests.** We use your information to get to know what your preferences might be so we can improve our offering to you and so that your experience with us is more relevant and personal. We may combine information we get from you with information about you we get from third parties, including to analyse customer behaviour. 

**To monitor and improve our products, services, and websites.** We analyse your information to improve our understanding of you and our customer base in general. We do this so that we can make better decisions about our services, advertising, products and content, based on a more informed picture of how our customers use our current services, and to provide you with a more customised experience. 

**To prevent or detect unlawful behaviour or to protect or enforce legal rights.** For example, we may use your information to prevent ticket touting, misuse of our intellectual property, or fraud (including credit card fraud and fraud we think has happened during a sweepstakes or promotion or at an event) or other crimes. If you are evicted from one of our events we may retain your details and you may be refused entry to any of our future events. 

**For security purposes.** We may use your information to protect the security of our company, employees, our customers, third parties and/or our/their property (including any events you may attend and our websites) as permitted by law. 

**For market research purposes.** We may contact you as part of market research we are carrying out. You may choose not to participate. 

**To provide you with tailored advertising and online behavioural advertising.** We may work with other companies to show you advertisements we think you may find relevant and useful. This may include advertisements displayed on our own websites or apps, or advertisements from us displayed on other companies’ sites. The advertisements you see may be based on information collected by us or third parties and/or may be based on your activities on our websites or third party sites. The second type of advertising is called ‘online or third party behavioural advertising’. Please see our [Cookies Policy](http://www.livenation.co.uk/cookies) for more information and the choices you have. 

**For marketing purposes.** Where you’ve agreed, you may be contacted by us by email, text message, telephone or other means with information or offers regarding our upcoming events, products or services (including newsletters). We may also send you information or offers on behalf of other businesses, but when we do this, we do not give those businesses your name and address. 

**As otherwise permitted by law.** In limited circumstances, we may also use your information for other purposes where permitted by law. 

### You have certain choices about how we use your information 

When you create an account, purchase tickets or download our apps, we may ask for your **consent** in order to collect, process or use your personal information for specified purposes. 

If you wish to withdraw any consent you have provided to us for such use of your personal information, you can deactivate your account online or please contact us or tell us about your preferences using the methods described in this section. 

_You understand that if you choose not to give us consents, or if you withdraw consents, you may not be able to take advantage of one or more features we offer. ****_

In addition to contacting us, you can **opt out** in the following ways:

**You can opt out of receiving marketing communications.** To stop receiving marketing communications, you can change your preferences within your account or follow the instructions in any messages you get. Your device settings should provide you with instructions on how to turn off push notifications. It may take about ten days to process your request. Don't worry! Even if you opt out of getting marketing messages, we will still be sure to send you transactional messages. For example, we may still contact you about your orders. 

**You can opt out of receiving our newsletters.** To stop receiving our newsletters you can change your preference within your account or follow the instructions in any newsletter you get from us.

**You can control and opt out of the use of cookies and tracking tools.** To learn how to manage how we use cookies and other tracking tools, please click [here](http://www.livenation.co.uk/cookies). 

**You can control and opt out of us using tools on your devices.** For example, you can turn off the GPS locator or push notifications by using the settings on your phone. Each push notification has an "unsubscribe" link.

**You can change your marketing preferences with our Event Partners** (e.g. opt out of receiving marketing e-mails from them) by contacting them directly.

### We may share your information with the following third parties 

**Within the Live Nation family of companies.** We may share any or all of your information with our group companies for any of the purposes referred to in this Policy.

**Our Event Partners.** We may share any of your information with our other Event Partners so that they can also run the event for which tickets have been purchased, analyse customer behaviour, provide a better service and support to customers, and for any other purpose described in our Event Partners’ privacy policies (including marketing). You should read those policies to learn how they treat your information. 

**Selected third parties.** If you consented to be contacted by email or other means by selected third parties, we may provide your information to the third parties we select, and these third parties may use this information for their marketing or advertising purposes. Where you’ve agreed to receiving information directly from selected third parties these parties may include charities and retail companies for example, companies offering financial, health, leisure or subscription services.

**Our third party service providers.** We may share your information with third parties so that they can provide services to us (e.g. a mailing house, a courier, a call centre provider, or a market research company), but where we do we will put in place a written agreement protecting your information. 

**Third parties who provide goods and services purchased by you.** Your information may also be shared with relevant third parties offering goods and services you have purchased through our website (e.g. ticket insurance or merchandise) so that they can process and fulfil your orders (including by contacting you). 

**If we think we have to in order to comply with legal or regulatory requirements or to protect ourselves, Event Partners or third parties.** Where permitted by law, we may also share information requested by a government agency or other authorised body or organisation, to protect or enforce our rights or the rights of any Event Partner or third party, or in the detection and prevention of fraud (including credit card fraud and fraud we think has happened during a sweepstakes or promotion or at an event) and other crimes. 

**Any successor to all or part of our business.** Where permitted by law, we may give a successor your information to use for the purposes set out in this Policy - and we may also give a potential successor this information - but only where we have taken reasonable steps to ensure the security and confidentiality of that information. 

### **Our sites and apps are not intended for children.**

Our sites and apps are meant for adults. We do not knowingly collect personal  information from children. If you are a parent or legal guardian and think your child has given us information, you can contact us. **_ _**

### We use standard security measures

**We have security measures in place to protect your information.** The standard security measures we use will depend on the type of information collected. However, the Internet is not 100% secure. We cannot promise that your use of our sites will be completely safe. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. This includes not sharing your passwords.

### **You can deal with us anonymously in certain circumstances**

When creating an account with Live Nation we ask you to provide your name, an email addresses and a password. To create an account you do not have to provide us with your real name or an email address that identifies you but if you wish to use that account to buy tickets we will need to know your real name and billing details so we can process your ticket purchase. 

If you contact us with a general query you can also do so anonymously but if you wish to discuss your account with us we will ask for information to identify and verify your account.

At some of our events, we use wristbands equipped with technology which allows you to access the event and make cashless payments by holding the wristband against a reader. You can use these wristbands without providing your personal information but if you want to get refund of the outstanding balance at the end of the event you will have to provide your information. 

### We may transfer your information to other countries

The transfer of your information for use in line with this Policy and [Cookies Policy](http://www.livenation.co.uk/cookies) may involve the transfer of your information to other countries (including outside Europe). The laws of other countries to which your information is transferred may not provide the same level of protection for your personal information as the law of your home country. We do, however, put in place appropriate technical and contractual protections for your personal information in accordance with applicable laws.

### We may link to third party sites or services we don't control

**If you click on one of those links, you will be taken to websites we do not control.** This Policy does not apply to the privacy practices of those websites. Read the privacy policy of other websites carefully. We are not responsible for these third party sites.

Feel free to contact us if you have any questions, complaints or require a copy of information we hold about you

If you have any questions or complaints about this Policy or any privacy concerns, or would like to request copies of the information we hold about you, please [contact us](http://www.livenation.co.uk/CustomerService):

Please do not include your credit card number or other financial or sensitive information in your email. 

To correct, amend or update information you have given us, or in order to withdraw a consent you have given us, you can log into your account or you can [contact us](http://www.livenation.co.uk/CustomerService). **_ _**

### What we will do if there is an update to this policy

From time to time we may change our privacy practices. We will notify you of any changes to this Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website. It will have a different date and version number from the one set out below. Please check our site periodically for updates.

### Who we are

We are Live Nation (Music) UK Limited and its group companies. You can find out more about us [here.](http://www.livenation.co.uk/about)

Last Updated: April 2015
